<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Kategoria: Recenzje | Toruń JUG]]></title>
  <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/categories/recenzje/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-12T16:38:56+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://torun.jug.pl/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Toruń JUG]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recenzja książki: BDD in Action]]></title>
    <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/08/12/recenzja-ksiazki-bdd-in-action/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-12T16:26:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/08/12/recenzja-ksiazki-bdd-in-action</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tadeusz Zalewski</strong> jest kolejnym śmiałkiem, który odważył się napisać recenzję książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej darmowy egzemplarz. Wybór padł na <em>BDD in Action: Behavior-Driven Development for the whole software lifecycle</em> autorstwa Johna Fergusona Smarta.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Książka</h3>

<p><img class="no-border book-cover" src="/images/reviews/books/bdd-in-action.jpg" />
<strong><em>BDD in Action: Behavior-Driven Development for the whole software lifecycle</em></strong></p>

<p>Behavior-Driven Development starts with a&nbsp;simple idea: you can&rsquo;t write good software if you don&rsquo;t understand what it&rsquo;s supposed to do. BDD is a&nbsp;development process that helps you design better code by writing tests that describe the behavior of an&nbsp;application and its underlying requirements. With an&nbsp;emerging body of best practices with sophisticated new tools that assist in requirement analysis and test automation, BDD has become a&nbsp;hot, increasingly mainstream, approach. Done well, it helps you deliver higher quality software that creates business genuine value.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.manning.com/smart/" target="_blank"><em>BDD in Action</em></a> teaches you the Behavior-Driven Development model and shows you how to integrate it into your existing development process. First you&rsquo;ll learn how to apply BDD to requirements analysis to define features that focus your development efforts on underlying business goals. Then, you&rsquo;ll discover how to automate acceptance criteria and use tests to guide and report on the development process. Along the way, you&rsquo;ll apply BDD principles at the coding level to write more maintainable and better documented code.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Autor</h3>

<p><strong>John Ferguson Smart</strong> is a&nbsp;specialist in BDD, automated testing, and software life cycle development optimization. A&nbsp;well-known speaker and writer, John is the author of <em>Java Power Tools</em> and <em>Jenkins: The Definitive Guide</em>.</p>

<h3>Recenzja</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>This book is exactly what I have been looking for since I was interested in BDD. It describes the whole process of BDD from business part of organization to IT part. It describes you not only "how to build software right" but also "how to build right software". The book has a&nbsp;lot of examples for Java, .NET, JS, Groovy practitioners.</p>
  <p>In first two chapters author introduces BDD with some theories and gives us snapshot project which present what we can achieve. He usees JBehave, Thucydides and Spock.</p>
  <p>Next three chapters could be quite difficult for developers because they don't contain any source code. They treat about "how to build right software", in practice how to transform business goals into user stories. You can learn few techniques how to talk with business as a&nbsp;developer to extract software requirements and prepare foundations for your application.</p>
  <p>Next four chapters are about automation scenarios from above chapters. You can learn few tools:
    <ul>
      <li>JBehave, Cucumber for Java,</li>
      <li>Behave for Python,</li>
      <li>SpecFlow for .NET,</li>
      <li>Cucumber-JS for JavaScript</li>
    </ul>
  which help you to do this. You also will learn how to improve test automation, how to test UI layer using Selenium WebDriver and how to write acceptance tests for non-UI requirements, ie. RESTful API.
  Then we go to the lowest level – BDD in unit testing. This four chapters are most interesting for developers because we can learn a&nbsp;lot of techniques which help us "build software right". There are also a&nbsp;lot of examples of code and tools ie. FEST-Assert (why not AssertJ), Jasmine, RSpec, parametrized testing in JUnit. But there is nothing about negative cases testing or exception testing (ie. catch-exception library has BDD support).</p>
  <p>First of the last two chapters treats about using automated tests as living documentation and support developing process management. Author uses Thucydides and Cucumber Report in examples.</p>
  <p>The last one teaches us how to place BDD in continuous delivery process and how to obtain functionality and performance using Jenkins and Selenium Grid.</p>
  <p>Rating: 5/5</p>
</blockquote>


<h3>Recenzent</h3>

<p><img class="no-border reviewer-face" src="/images/reviews/reviewers/zalewski-tadeusz.jpg" />
<strong>Tadeusz Zalewski</strong></p>

<p>Programista i&nbsp;projektant w&nbsp;Agora S.A. Obecnie rozwija się w&nbsp;obszarach takich jak BDD oraz DDD w&nbsp;celu poprawy jakości relacji biznes&nbsp;&lt;=>&nbsp;IT w&nbsp;procesie wytwarzania oprogramowania.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Szukamy kolejnych odważnych</h3>

<p>Jeśli ktoś z&nbsp;Was chciałby otrzymać kopię wybranej przez siebie książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej recenzję, to zapraszamy na odpowiedni <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/torunjug/QvoMIJhDM0M/discussion" target="_blank">wątek na naszej grupie dyskusyjnej</a>. Dzięki <a href="http://torun.jug.pl/partners/">partnerstwu</a> z&nbsp;wydawnictwami <a href="http://www.manning.com" target="_blank">Manning Publications Co.</a>, <a href="http://oreilly.com" target="_blank">O’Reilly Media</a> i <a href="http://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank">Packt Publishing</a> macie do wyboru bardzo szeroki wachlarz książek o&nbsp;różnorodnej tematyce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recenzja książki: Functional Programming in Java]]></title>
    <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/07/28/recenzja-ksiazki-functional-programming-in-java/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-28T18:54:33+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/07/28/recenzja-ksiazki-functional-programming-in-java</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jest nam bardzo miło poinformować, że&nbsp;znalazł się pierwszy odważny ochotnik, który zgłosił się i&nbsp;napisał subiektywną recenzję wybranej przez siebie książki. Honorowy tytuł &ldquo;pierwszego recenzenta toruńskiego JUGa&rdquo; otrzymuje&hellip; <strong>Michał Jaśtak</strong> :)</p>

<p>Michał wziął pod lupę książkę <em>Functional Programming in Java: Harnessing the Power of Java&nbsp;8 Lambda Expressions</em>, której autorem jest Venkat Subramaniam.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Książka</h3>

<p><img class="no-border book-cover" src="/images/reviews/books/functional-programming-in-java.jpg" />
<strong><em>Functional Programming in Java: Harnessing the Power of Java&nbsp;8 Lambda Expressions</em></strong></p>

<p>Get ready to program in a&nbsp;whole new way. <a href="http://pragprog.com/book/vsjava8/functional-programming-in-java" target="_blank"><em>Functional Programming in&nbsp;Java</em></a> will help you quickly get on top of the new, essential Java&nbsp;8 language features and the functional style that will change and improve your code. This short, targeted book will help you make the paradigm shift from the old imperative way to a&nbsp;less error-prone, more elegant, and concise coding style that&rsquo;s also a&nbsp;breeze to parallelize. You&rsquo;ll explore the syntax and semantics of&nbsp;lambda expressions, method and constructor references, and functional interfaces. You&rsquo;ll design and write applications better using the new standards in Java&nbsp;8 and the JDK.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Autor</h3>

<p><strong>Dr. Venkat Subramaniam</strong> is an&nbsp;award-winning author, founder of Agile Developer, Inc., and a&nbsp;professor at the University of Houston. He&rsquo;s a&nbsp;regularly invited speaker at international conferences, a&nbsp;Java Champion, and has received the&nbsp;JavaOne Rockstar award multiple times.</p>

<h3>Recenzja</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>I had a&nbsp;pleasure to listen to couple of Venkat's talks, and IMHO he is probably the one and only speaker in the World, who could give a&nbsp;talk about preparing spaghetti to 1000 senior developers, and after that, each one of them desire to be spaghetti developer till end of the days ;)</p>
  <p>This book is dangerous, same way as Venkat's talks. You have to be aware, that when you read it, the one and only thing you'll desire to do will be writing lambda expressions.</p>
  <p>This book is a&nbsp;travel guide for those who have enough of development in imperative way. Venkat will guide you gently from imperative solutions of some daily development problems into functional versions of those solutions.</p>
  <p>This book is like written by your best Friend, who really cares about the way you develop your code. Venkat will advise you to be more declarative, promote immutability, avoid side effects, prefer expressions over statements, and design with Higher Order Functions. Even more, he will explain how the above rules are closing you to functional programming.</p>
  <p>This book isn't a&nbsp;crime fiction, but you will not be able to stop reading about designing with lambda expressions, recursion optimisation, parallelization, mapping and reducing, until you'll find who killed your last software development efforts.</p>
  <p>This book isn't about easy things, but if you want to learn about something new, or systematise and extend your knowledge, you should choose your Mentor carefully. Believe me, Venkat and his book is a&nbsp;really good choice.</p>
  <p>Rating: 5/5</p>
</blockquote>


<h3>Recenzent</h3>

<p><img class="no-border reviewer-face" src="/images/reviews/reviewers/jastak-michal.jpg" />
<strong>Michał Jaśtak</strong></p>

<p>Programista Java z&nbsp;wieloletnim doświadczeniem, pracujący obecnie na stanowisku CTO w&nbsp;firmie AIS.PL. W&nbsp;wolnych chwilach dzieli się własnymi spostrzeżeniami na swoim blogu (<a href="http://vard-lokkur.blogspot.com" target="_blank">Warlock&rsquo;s Thoughts</a>) oraz Twitterze (<a href="https://twitter.com/vardlokkur" target="_blank">@vardlokkur</a>). Prywatnie &ndash; fan <a href="http://eu.battle.net/sc2/pl/profile/933084/1/Anakin/" target="_blank">Protossów</a> ;)</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Szukamy kolejnych odważnych</h3>

<p>Jeśli ktoś z&nbsp;Was chciałby otrzymać kopię wybranej przez siebie książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej recenzję, to zapraszamy na odpowiedni <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/torunjug/QvoMIJhDM0M/discussion" target="_blank">wątek na naszej grupie dyskusyjnej</a>. Dzięki <a href="/partners/">partnerstwu</a> z&nbsp;wydawnictwami <a href="http://www.manning.com" target="_blank">Manning Publications Co.</a>, <a href="http://oreilly.com" target="_blank">O'Reilly Media</a> i <a href="http://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank">Packt Publishing</a> macie do wyboru bardzo szeroki wachlarz książek o&nbsp;różnorodnej tematyce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
