<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Kategoria: Recenzje | Toruń JUG]]></title>
  <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/categories/recenzje/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-29T06:13:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://torun.jug.pl/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Toruń JUG]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recenzja książki: Effective Modern C++]]></title>
    <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/2016/03/02/recenzja-ksiazki-effective-modern-c-plus-plus/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-02T07:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://torun.jug.pl/news/2016/03/02/recenzja-ksiazki-effective-modern-c-plus-plus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Minął ponad rok od czasu opublikowania poprzedniej recenzji. Autorem ostatniej był Sebastian Łaskawiec. Autorem dzisiejszej&hellip; <strong>Sebastian Łaskawiec</strong> :) Tym razem wziął pod lupę książkę <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920033707.do" target="_blank"><em>Effective Modern C++</em></a> autorstwa Scotta Meyersa To już trzecia recenzja na koncie Sebastiana i&nbsp;jednocześnie <a href="/news/categories/recenzje/">siódma</a> na koncie wszystkich naszych JUGowiczów.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Książka</h3>

<p><img class="no-border book-cover" src="/images/reviews/books/effective-modern-c-plus-plus.jpg" />
<strong><em>Effective Modern C++</em></strong></p>

<p>Coming to grips with C++11 and C++14 is more than a matter of familiarizing yourself with the features they introduce (e.g., auto type declarations, move semantics, lambda expressions, and concurrency support). The challenge is learning to use those features effectively—so that your software is correct, efficient, maintainable, and portable. That’s where this practical book comes in. It describes how to write truly great software using C++11 and C++14 — i.e. using modern C++.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Autor</h3>

<p><strong>Scott Douglas Meyers</strong> is an American author and software consultant, specializing in the C++ computer programming language. He is known for his Effective C++ book series. He is a frequent speaker at conferences and trade shows. He holds a Ph.D. in computer science from Brown University and M.S. in computer science from Stanford University.</p>

<h3>Recenzja</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>
    <strong>Content</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    The book describes new language features introduced in C++11 and 14.
  </p>
  <p>
    The first paragraph explains how type resolution works in C++, which might be considered as an introduction to the second paragraph - auto types. The third paragraph is dedicated to several small improvements in C++11/14, like aliases, nullptrs or function overrides. Next paragraph is fully dedicated to smart pointers and their different use cases. Paragraph number five introduces std::move and std::forward concepts. Lambda expressions are covered in paragraph six and seventh introduces new concurrency API (Atomics). The last paragraph covers some minor tweaks.
  </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Writing style</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    The book is organized into items (similarly to "Effective Java"). Multiple items form paragraphs which cover broader topic (such as concurrency). All items are clearly defined and contain a lot of code snippets, which makes them easier to understand. The book is very concise and to-the-point and defiantly dedicated for intermediate or advanced C++ programmers who want to learn new language features.
  </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Conclusion and recommendation</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    This book is like manual for new C/C++ features. I often get back to it when I want to use something new. Very strict language and a lot of code examples help to understand described concepts. From my perspective the best part was about Atomics. Dealing with multithreded code (especially targeted for multiple runtimes) was a nightmare before introducing concurrency features. It is also worth mentioning that this book is not meant for beginners. The reader needs to have at least some intermediate experience to learn more advanced concepts shown in the book.
  </p>
  <p>Rating: 5/5</p>
</blockquote>


<h3>Recenzent</h3>

<p><img class="no-border reviewer-face" src="/images/reviews/reviewers/laskawiec-sebastian.jpg" />
<strong>Sebastian Łaskawiec</strong></p>

<p>Senior Software Developer in Red Hat interested in JEE containers and Caching technologies who spends most of his free time on home brewing, ice skating or skiing.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Szukamy kolejnych odważnych</h3>

<p>Jeśli ktoś z&nbsp;Was chciałby otrzymać kopię wybranej przez siebie książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej recenzję, to zapraszamy do odpowiedniego <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/torunjug/QvoMIJhDM0M/discussion" target="_blank">wątku na naszej grupie dyskusyjnej</a>. Dzięki <a href="http://torun.jug.pl/partners/">partnerstwu</a> z&nbsp;wydawnictwami <a href="http://www.manning.com" target="_blank">Manning Publications Co.</a>, <a href="http://oreilly.com" target="_blank">O'Reilly Media</a> oraz <a href="http://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank">Packt Publishing</a> macie do wyboru bardzo szeroki wachlarz książek o&nbsp;różnorodnej tematyce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recenzja książki: Java 8 Lambdas]]></title>
    <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/2015/01/05/recenzja-ksiazki-java-8-lambdas/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-05T12:52:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://torun.jug.pl/news/2015/01/05/recenzja-ksiazki-java-8-lambdas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Witamy Was gorąco w&nbsp;Nowym Roku i&nbsp;życzymy samych słonecznych dni! Na dobry początek proponujemy zapoznać się z&nbsp;recenzją książki <em>Java 8 Lambdas</em>. Autorem książki jest Richard Warburton, autorem recenzji &ndash; <strong>Sebastian Łaskawiec</strong>. To druga recenzja na koncie Sebastiana i&nbsp;jednocześnie <a href="/news/categories/recenzje/">szósta</a> na koncie wszystkich naszych JUGowiczów.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Książka</h3>

<p><img class="no-border book-cover" src="/images/reviews/books/java-8-lambdas.jpg" />
<strong><em>Java 8 Lambdas: Functional Programming for the Masses</em></strong></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re a&nbsp;developer with core Java SE skills, this <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920030713.do" target="_blank">hands-on book</a> takes you through the language changes in Java 8 triggered by the addition of lambda expressions. You&rsquo;ll learn through code examples, exercises, and fluid explanations how these anonymous functions will help you write simple, clean, library-level code that solves business problems.</p>

<p>Lambda expressions are a&nbsp;fairly simple change to Java, and the first part of the book shows you how to use them properly. Later chapters show you how lambda functions help you improve performance with parallelism, write simpler concurrent code, and model your domain more accurately, including building better DSLs.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Autor</h3>

<p><strong>Richard Warburton</strong> is an empirical technologist and solver of deep-dive technical problems. He has professionally worked on static analysis problems, verifying part of a&nbsp; compiler and developing advanced automated bug detection technology. More recently his career has been focussed on data analytics for high performance computing. He is a&nbsp;leader in the London Java Community, sits on their JCP Committee and organises the Adopt-a-JSR programs for Lambdas and Date and Time in Java&nbsp;8. Richard is also a&nbsp;known conference speaker, having talked at JavaOne, DevoxxUK and JAX London. He obtained a&nbsp;PhD in Computer Science from The University of Warwick where his research focussed on compiler theory.</p>

<h3>Recenzja</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>
    <strong>Content</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    The book describes practical approach to new features introduced in Java&nbsp;8. Most of the book is dedicated to Lambdas but the author also described other language and library add-ons.
  </p>
  <p>
    The first two paragraphs contain introduction to Lambda expressions and explain why Java needs them. Third paragraph presents Stream's key concepts. All operations (like map, filter or flatMap) are explained using very descriptive examples. Fourth paragraph goes into the details of other Java&nbsp;8 concepts like Optional, default/static methods in the interfaces and binary compatibility. After introducing those additional concepts the author goes into the details of collections and Collectors (starting from easy topics like element ordering and finishing on advanced like parallelism vs concurrency, debugging or refactoring). The last two paragraphs of the book describes architectural design patterns using Lambda expressions and shows some real life examples for topics like nonblocking I/O.
  </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Writing style</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    <em>Java&nbsp;8 Lambdas</em> is written using very easy to learn style. All concepts are briefly described theoretically and explained in detail using examples. There is also a&nbsp;GitHub repository with exercises for presented topics. The author focuses on practical approach for Java&nbsp;8 features rather than theoretical aspects.
  </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Conclusion and recommendation</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    <em>Java&nbsp;8 Lambdas</em> is a&nbsp;must-have book for those who start using new features introduced in Java&nbsp;8. The author clearly assumes basic understanding of previous Java features, so I wouldn't recommend this book for beginners. On the other hand an experienced programmer will feel comfortable with key concepts of Lambdas after reading less then forty pages (!!).
  </p>
  <p>
    I highly recommend reading this book in two parts. At first, read basic concepts and get familiar with them (paragraphs 1-4). Do some exercises or ever better - get involved into some project which uses Java&nbsp;8. Finally, finish reading the advanced topics of the book.
  </p>
  <p>Rating: 5/5</p>
</blockquote>


<h3>Recenzent</h3>

<p><img class="no-border reviewer-face" src="/images/reviews/reviewers/laskawiec-sebastian.jpg" />
<strong>Sebastian Łaskawiec</strong></p>

<p>Senior Software Developer in Red Hat interested in JEE containers and Caching technologies who spends most of his free time on home brewing, ice skating or skiing.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Szukamy kolejnych odważnych</h3>

<p>Jeśli ktoś z&nbsp;Was chciałby otrzymać kopię wybranej przez siebie książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej recenzję, to zapraszamy do odpowiedniego <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/torunjug/QvoMIJhDM0M/discussion" target="_blank">wątku na naszej grupie dyskusyjnej</a>. Dzięki <a href="http://torun.jug.pl/partners/">partnerstwu</a> z&nbsp;wydawnictwami <a href="http://www.manning.com" target="_blank">Manning Publications Co.</a>, <a href="http://oreilly.com" target="_blank">O'Reilly Media</a> oraz <a href="http://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank">Packt Publishing</a> macie do wyboru bardzo szeroki wachlarz książek o&nbsp;różnorodnej tematyce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recenzja książki: Three.js Essentials]]></title>
    <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/10/14/recenzja-ksiazki-three-js-essentials/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-14T05:26:56+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/10/14/recenzja-ksiazki-three-js-essentials</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kolejna recenzja książki na koncie toruńskiego JUGowicza! Tym razem <strong>Maciej Mikulski</strong> podzielił się swoimi wrażeniami z&nbsp;lektury <em>Three.js Essentials</em> autorstwa Josa Dirksena.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Książka</h3>

<p><img class="no-border book-cover" src="/images/reviews/books/three-js-essentials.jpg" />
<strong><em>Three.js Essentials</em></strong></p>

<p>Create beautiful visualizations and 3D scenes using Three.js with this practical, <a href="https://www.packtpub.com/web-development/threejs-essentials" target="_blank">example-rich book</a>. Learn all the core concepts of Three.js, and whether you are targeting mobile devices or desktop browsers, you will gain the necessary skills to build a&nbsp;3D application and improve web performance.</p>

<p>From setting up a&nbsp;development environment and creating your first Three.js scene, you will quickly dive into more complex scene-making. Discover a&nbsp;variety of possible scenes from how to make a&nbsp;rotating planet with data overlay to mini games. Through these examples, you will be shown an array of skills from using materials, controls, and lighting to creating particle systems and geometries from scratch.</p>

<p>By the end of this book, you&rsquo;ll be able to effectively and confidently create 3D scenes using different lights and materials, create visualizations using particle systems, animate web pages, and incorporate Blender in your 3D workflow.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Autor</h3>

<p><strong>Jos Dirksen</strong> has worked as a&nbsp;software developer and architect for more than a&nbsp;decade. He has quite a&nbsp;lot of experience in a&nbsp;large range of technologies that range from backend technologies, such as Java and Scala, to frontend development using HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript. Besides working with these technologies, he also regularly speaks at conferences and likes to write about new and interesting technologies on his blog. He also likes to experiment with new technologies and see how they can be best used to create beautiful data visualizations, the results of which you can see on his blog at <a href="http://www.smartjava.org" target="_blank">smartjava.org</a>.</p>

<h3>Recenzja</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>
    <em>Three.js Essentials</em> by Jos Dirksen (published by PacktPub) is a&nbsp;great introduction to using Three.js library that enables you to render interactive 3D graphics in modern web browsers. Rendering 3D in browsers without plugins become available thanks to WebGL API that has been implemented in all major browsers on desktop computers as well as on mobile ones. Using the API is complicated so the best way to get it running is by using library that takes care of browser differences and gives you unified methods for dealing with common tasks. The best choice is the open source library Three.js and book by Jos Dirkson is the best introduction for this.
  </p>
  <p>
    Author walks through all essential steps needed to build a&nbsp;3D scene in a&nbsp;browser. Every chapter of the book presented in the form of tutorial with accompanying code examples teaches basic techniques and shows direction for further exploration. First chapters shows how to establish basic 3D scenes with lighting and controls, followed by creating models and adding textures, normal maps, specular maps and more. Next you will learn how to create geometries programmatically with help of 3rd party tools like trees or noise generators. On top of this author teaches you how to use Three.js to visualize Audio Data with particle system.
  </p>
  <p>
    Book covers also CSS3DRenderer that allows building 3D views with CSS3 3D Transformations instead of WebGL Renderer.
  </p>
  <p>
    Last chapter describes basic workflow for exporting models and animations from Blender - 3D modeling open source tool. Blender combined with Three.js enables you to bring 3D models and animations to a&nbsp;browser very quickly. For example this is a&nbsp;great way for bringing 3D scanned models into your website.
  </p>
  <p>
    Step by step tutorials from the book help you understanding how Three.js works and quickly build skills needed to use it on your own projects. Only drawback I found while going through the book is that you can find missed steps while going through more advanced tasks, so you have to dive into JavaScript examples attached to the book to find differences between consecutive lessons. On the other hand if you have basic understanding of JavaScript you will find these in no time and this exercise will help you better understand Three.js.
  </p>
  <p>
    In my opinion this book is a&nbsp;great start for everyone interested into bringing 3D to web. I would recommend this book for web developers that want to expand their skill set, 3D designers that would like to present their models directly on the web and game developers researching replacement for plugin based (Flash, Unity) 3D rendering in browsers. Think about the possibilities for combining web 3D with upcoming technologies like Google Cardboard or Samsung VR that will possibly bring 3D viewing experience to casual users.
  </p>
  <p>Rating: 4/5</p>
</blockquote>


<h3>Recenzent</h3>

<p><img class="no-border reviewer-face" src="/images/reviews/reviewers/mikulski-maciej.jpg" />
<strong>Maciej Mikulski</strong></p>

<p>Web i&nbsp;Android developer działający pod szyldem <a href="http://sparklab.pl" target="_blank">Sparklab.pl</a>. Łączy pasję programistyczną z&nbsp;działalnością biznesową i&nbsp;marketingową. Współzałożyciel <a href="http://missiontorun.org" target="_blank">Mission: ToRun</a> &ndash; toruńskich spotkań dla przedsiębiorców.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Szukamy kolejnych odważnych</h3>

<p>Jeśli ktoś z&nbsp;Was chciałby otrzymać kopię wybranej przez siebie książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej recenzję, to zapraszamy do odpowiedniego <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/torunjug/QvoMIJhDM0M/discussion" target="_blank">wątku na naszej grupie dyskusyjnej</a>. Dzięki <a href="http://torun.jug.pl/partners/">partnerstwu</a> z&nbsp;wydawnictwami <a href="http://www.manning.com" target="_blank">Manning Publications Co.</a>, <a href="http://oreilly.com" target="_blank">O'Reilly Media</a>, <a href="http://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank">Packt Publishing</a> i&nbsp;<a href="https://www.apress.com" target="_blank">Apress</a> macie do wyboru bardzo szeroki wachlarz książek o&nbsp;różnorodnej tematyce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recenzja książki: Continuous Enterprise Development in Java]]></title>
    <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/09/24/recenzja-ksiazki-continuous-enterprise-development-in-java/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-24T05:51:22+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/09/24/recenzja-ksiazki-continuous-enterprise-development-in-java</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sebastian Łaskawiec</strong>, którego mieliśmy przyjemność słuchać na naszym <a href="/news/2014/06/07/spotkanie-4/">czwartym spotkaniu</a>, popełnił recenzję książki <em>Continuous Enterprise Development in&nbsp;Java: Testable Solutions with Arquillian</em> autorstwa Andrew Lee Rubingera i&nbsp;Aslaka Knutsena. To już czwarta <a href="/news/categories/recenzje/">recenzja</a> na koncie naszych JUGowiczów!</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Książka</h3>

<p><img class="no-border book-cover" src="/images/reviews/books/continuous-enterprise-development-in-java.jpg" />
<strong><em>Continuous Enterprise Development in&nbsp;Java: Testable Solutions with Arquillian</em></strong></p>

<p>Learn a&nbsp;use-case approach for developing Java enterprise applications in a&nbsp;continuously test-driven fashion. With <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920025368.do" target="_blank">this hands-on guide</a>, authors and JBoss project leaders Andrew Lee Rubinger and Aslak Knutsen show you how to build high-level components, from persistent storage to the user interface, using the Arquillian testing platform and several other JBoss projects and tools.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Autorzy</h3>

<p><strong>Andrew Lee Rubinger</strong>, a&nbsp;Senior Software Engineer at JBoss, a&nbsp;Division of Red Hat, primarily responsible for development of the company&rsquo;s EJB 3.x implementation. He was an early adopter of Java EE technologies and an active contributor in the tech community.</p>

<p><strong>Aslak Knutsen</strong>, the project lead of Arquillian, is a&nbsp;Senior SoftwareEngineer at JBoss, by Red Hat. He&rsquo;s involved in projects such as Arquillian, ShrinkWrap, Weld and Seam 3, one of the founders of theJBoss Testing initiative and a&nbsp;speaker at major industry conferences including Devoxx, JavaOne, Jazoon, JFokus, and Geecon.</p>

<h3>Recenzja</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>
    <strong>Content</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    The book covers theoretical and practical aspects of programming using modern tools and JEE technologies. The first paragraph introduces basics concepts of software development and shows that writing tests is actually part of creating the software. In the second paragraph the authors introduce basic tooling and explains briefly how each framework works. Along to standard tools like Git or Maven there are some others - less known - like JBoss Forge or Red Hat OpenShift. In the next paragraph the authors define requirements for building application which will be developed throughout the book (No! I won't tell you what it is - check out yourself!). Next few paragraphs show how to build and test different layers of the application - starting from relational database and NoSQL frameworks, going through REST services and ending with testing user interface. The last paragraph describes things, which should be considered when deploying application on production.
  </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Writing style</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    Andrew and Aslak wrote this publication in workbook style. Each chapter is preceded by theoretical introduction. Shortly after that the authors present given concepts (like graph databases) in context of application requirements, which are followed by the implementation and testing. This approach is very convenient for less advanced readers. On the other hand experts may find many very useful tricks during the implementation phase.
  </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Conclusion and recommendation</strong>
  </p>
  <p>
    When I started reading <em>Continuous Enterprise Development in Java</em> I thought this would be a&nbsp;detailed Arquillian guide. Instead, Andrew and Aslak took me for a&nbsp;journey of most recently used technologies and JEE spec. Many of those tools I started to use in my everyday job (like JBoss Forge). After reading this book I have a basic idea how to test JS based web application front-ends - which is something new for a strong back-end developer - like me.
  </p>
  <p>
    This publication also broadened my knowledge of Arquillian. Many concepts were explained in details - for example views in Shrinkwrap framework. Understanding such concepts is the key for writing maintainable test code.
  </p>
  <p>
    I strongly recommend this book for every developer who wants to learn new things about modern tools, technologies and testing approach. If you are creating an&nbsp;enterprise or web application - this book is definitely for you.
  </p>
  <p>Rating: 5/5</p>
</blockquote>


<h3>Recenzent</h3>

<p><img class="no-border reviewer-face" src="/images/reviews/reviewers/laskawiec-sebastian.jpg" />
<strong>Sebastian Łaskawiec</strong></p>

<p>Senior Software Engineer w firmie Red Hat, interesujący się kontenerami JEE oraz pisaniem dobrego kodu. W&nbsp;wolnym czasie pasjonat nart, łyżew, rolek, a&nbsp;także domowego piwa i&nbsp;dobrych gier.</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Szukamy kolejnych odważnych</h3>

<p>Jeśli ktoś z&nbsp;Was chciałby otrzymać kopię wybranej przez siebie książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej recenzję, to zapraszamy do odpowiedniego <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/torunjug/QvoMIJhDM0M/discussion" target="_blank">wątku na naszej grupie dyskusyjnej</a>. Dzięki <a href="http://torun.jug.pl/partners/">partnerstwu</a> z&nbsp;wydawnictwami <a href="http://www.manning.com" target="_blank">Manning Publications Co.</a>, <a href="http://oreilly.com" target="_blank">O'Reilly Media</a>, <a href="http://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank">Packt Publishing</a> i&nbsp;<a href="https://www.apress.com" target="_blank">Apress</a> macie do wyboru bardzo szeroki wachlarz książek o&nbsp;różnorodnej tematyce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recenzja książki: Functional JavaScript]]></title>
    <link href="http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/09/17/recenzja-ksiazki-functional-javascript/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-17T05:59:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://torun.jug.pl/news/2014/09/17/recenzja-ksiazki-functional-javascript</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mamy dla Was kolejną recenzję! <strong>Tomasz Bielawa</strong> zrecenzował książkę <em>Functional JavaScript: Introducing Functional Programming with Underscore.js</em> autorstwa Michaela Fogusa.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Książka</h3>

<p><img class="no-border book-cover" src="/images/reviews/books/functional-javascript.jpg" />
<strong><em>Functional JavaScript: Introducing Functional Programming with Underscore.js</em></strong></p>

<p>How can you overcome JavaScript language oddities and unsafe features? With <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920028857.do" target="_blank">this book</a>, you&rsquo;ll learn how to create code that&rsquo;s beautiful, safe, and simple to understand and test by using JavaScript&rsquo;s functional programming support. Author Michael Fogus shows you how to apply functional-style concepts with Underscore.js, a&nbsp;JavaScript library that facilitates functional programming techniques. Sample code is available on <a href="https://github.com/funjs/book-source" target="_blank">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>Fogus helps you think in a&nbsp;functional way to help you minimize complexity in the programs you build. If you&rsquo;re a&nbsp;JavaScript programmer hoping to learn functional programming techniques, or a&nbsp;functional programmer looking to learn JavaScript, this book is the ideal introduction.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Use applicative programming techniques with first-class functions</li>
  <li>Understand how and why you might leverage variable scoping and closures</li>
  <li>Delve into higher-order functions-and learn how they take other functions as arguments for maximum advantage</li>
  <li>Explore ways to compose new functions from existing functions</li>
  <li>Get around JavaScript's limitations for using recursive functions</li>
  <li>Reduce, hide, or eliminate the footprint of state change in your programs</li>
  <li>Practice flow-based programming with chains and functional pipelines</li>
  <li>Discover how to code without using classes</li>
</ul>


<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Autor</h3>

<p><strong>Michael Fogus</strong> is software developer with experience in distributed simulation, machine vision, and expert systems construction. He&rsquo;s actively involved in the Clojure and Scala communities.</p>

<h3>Recenzja</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>
    Over the last years the JavaScript returned to favor thanks to the popularity of HTML5 and jQuery. Many developers want to learn more about this language and to know JS's most significant libraries. Very popular products are distinguished by Jeremy Ashkenas. I think all developers heard about CoffeeScript or Backbone.js framework. Ashkenas also is the creator of UnderscoreJs library which provides a&nbsp;very useful utility functions.
  </p>
  <p>
    On the second hand, a&nbsp;very common tag is functional-style concept. At every step, terms like closures, currying, folding, come to our ears and eyes. Surely as a&nbsp;programmer you want to read a&nbsp;good book about it. This book should be absorbing, have good style of writing and practical examples. And first of all, author should have a&nbsp;considerable knowledge about things he describes.
  </p>
  <p>
    I think Michael Fogus, as a&nbsp;contributor to the Clojure and Underscore.js library is a&nbsp;right person in the right place. While reading, you can fell that the writer has a&nbsp;practical and real-life skills about functional programming and JS. You can see that he devoted much time to bite into this. For example Fogus bring us a&nbsp;precise chapter about closures. Yes! In JavaScript.  It's not the frequent term in a&nbsp;base of articles in a&nbsp;world's JS's blogs and books. It is not what a&nbsp;typical developer who writes only Dom-tree-JS-code knows.
  </p>
  <p>
    If you want to know how to use things like closures, currying, folding. Or you want to get knowledge about functions as units of behavior, functional recursion on data "table-like" (great thing!), recursion as a&nbsp;base of deeper understanding of a&nbsp;functional style, hiding mutable states, a&nbsp;way to implement laziness, this book may be your first step in an adventure of functional programming in (wait for it!) JavaScript. You will be familiarized with UnderscoreJs functions as a&nbsp;tools in everyday-coding-life.
  </p>
  <p>
    Honestly, the only thing that bothered me in this book is the small emphasis of graphic representation in highlighting important terms.
  </p>
  <p>
    Besides, "Functional JavaScript: Introducing Functional Programming with Underscore.js" assure many hours spending in reading interesting code, especially if reader will spend some hours to analyze written code and test it in IDE. Surely it should bear fruits in developer's future coding sessions.
  </p>
  <p>
    So, if anyone is interested in JavaScript and want to learn about functional programming techniques, this book is a&nbsp;very good start and may change perspective of seeing this language.
  </p>
  <p>Rating: 9/10</p>
</blockquote>


<h3>Recenzent</h3>

<p><img class="no-border reviewer-face" src="/images/reviews/reviewers/bielawa-tomasz.jpg" />
<strong>Tomasz Bielawa</strong></p>

<p>Programista i&nbsp;WebDeveloper, miłośnik wszelakich technologii frontendowych, muzyki oraz wszystkiego co można przeczytać. Można mnie znaleźć na Twitterze (<a href="https://twitter.com/bielawka" target="_blank">@bielawka</a>).</p>

<p><span class="clearfix"></span></p>

<h3>Szukamy kolejnych odważnych</h3>

<p>Jeśli ktoś z&nbsp;Was chciałby otrzymać kopię wybranej przez siebie książki w&nbsp;zamian za jej recenzję, to zapraszamy do odpowiedniego <a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/torunjug/QvoMIJhDM0M/discussion" target="_blank">wątku na naszej grupie dyskusyjnej</a>. Dzięki <a href="http://torun.jug.pl/partners/">partnerstwu</a> z&nbsp;wydawnictwami <a href="http://www.manning.com" target="_blank">Manning Publications Co.</a>, <a href="http://oreilly.com" target="_blank">O'Reilly Media</a> i <a href="http://www.packtpub.com" target="_blank">Packt Publishing</a> macie do wyboru bardzo szeroki wachlarz książek o&nbsp;różnorodnej tematyce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
